

# Samy CHBINOU

DevOps Build Workflow Engineer

Imp Juan, ANTIBES, FR

06 67 89 55 87

samy.chbinou@esna.cloud

https://chbinousamy.github.io/resume/resume.pdf

English, Italian, French

# **BACKGROUND**

## **ABOUT**

51 years old, Telecom & Software engineering education, I work in digital libraries (nowadays called DevOps), I write workflows & pipelines to Continuously Build, Test & Deliver Data Blocks. Moreover I follow younger people & digital enthousiasts who want to assert themselves in theses digital working fields.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Career Break, Relocation, Antibes 06

Oct. 2021 - Present

DevOps, NAVYA, La Défense 92

Sep, 2021 - Oct, 2021 1 month

NAVYA Drive delivers autonomous driving. In a Agile team of 5 persons I added Gitlab pipelines automation for Continuous Integration Tests. I also setup some Gitlab runners to handle load CI tests. Directly installed on Bare Metal and on some VMs, Virtualbox and AWS

- CI pipelines on Gitlab self hosted runners
- o Docker Buildx Python Containers

# Artificial Intelligence Engineer, VALEO, Créteil 94

May, 2021 - Jul, 2021 1 month

Valeo, In the transversal GEEDS entity, I assist in relocation of the R&D Datacenter from Paris to Créteil.

- Buildx Nvidia python Docker Containers
- Assistance in relocating a Datacenter from Paris to Creteil

# Platform Engineer, Nokia Bell Labs, Nozay 78

Oct, 2014 - Dec, 2020 6 years 2 months

Nokia Bell Labs, Cloud RAN Entity, Cloud for Radio Access Networks which interconnects UE radio devices such as Phones, IoT, Automotive, Virtual Reality User Equipments. I worked as freelance in a 'StartUp Garage'. I setup a On-Prems, PaaS context to make some tests on different types of Cloud Native 5G technologies: storage databases, ethernet over fiber, docker containers and kubernetes clusters, Machine Learning DevOps pipelines

- Wrote Statement Of Work définitions with scope of work, project objectives, task schedules and deliverables
- Benchmarking CPU Offloading on Nvidia GPU, Xilinx FPGA, Ethernet over Optical Fiber (RDMA)
- Java Kafka pipelines & NodeJS Express websockets
- N-Tiers Microservices Architectures: Docker, NoSQL Databases, Kubernetes, Cloud Native Serverless
- Machine learning and Neural Networks Data engineering

#### Career Break,

Apr, 2013 - Oct, 2014 1 year 5 months

### Software Test Engineer, Ercom Mobipass®, Vélizy 78

Dec, 2006 - Apr, 2013 6 years 3 months

Ercom, Mobipass®, I developped the Mobipass® project with a 5-100 person Télécom team to make it a recognized working software product. Mobipass® is a lab-based emulation product capable of precise reproduction of the behaviors of thousands of devices with mixed traffic calls and RF conditions experienced on a real network. Its easy-to-use GUI, advanced multi-UE channel emulator, integrated QoS and QoE test features and rich KPI capabilities make it a strong test and measurement addition for mobile network operators deploying advanced broadband networks. As Software engineer, I developed the GUI, User Interface in .NET C# language and did many tests on the TCP/IP Network.

- o Processing Network Datagram Blocks: Cut & Reassemble, Encode & Decode
- Object Oriented Programing to Design and Develop the UI in C#.NET
- Night Builds, Continuous Integration and Validation Tests

#### SKILLS

## **Object Programming Languages**



C# .NET

Java

## **Scripting Languages**



YAML

**JavaScript** 

Python

# **Database Languages**

SQL

NoSQL, Key Value Store

